DANIEL PITT

Front-End Software Engineer

💌 danielpitt1027@gmail.com 📞 +381 (65) 9017-943 💡 Novi Sad, Serbia

https://mostspace.github.io/daniel-portfolio/

Summary

Passionate front-end engineer with over 8 years of expertise in front-end development. Consistently challenges self and exerts effort to attain objectives. Possesses advanced proficiency in various programming languages, particularly front-end frameworks, and extensive knowledge of diverse database structures.

In the role of a front-end engineer, successfully developed numerous websites and mobile applications catering to multiple users. Completed various projects spanning a range of technical domains aligned with the unique business concepts of clients.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oct 2022 - present Tallinn, Estonia

Professional Freelancer, *GuruDesk*

- Successfully completed an e-commerce website with WordPress in a 15day timeframe, leading to a substantial increase in customer satisfaction.
- Consistently developed over 10 advanced user interfaces daily utilizing React and the Metronic Theme.

Dec 2019 – Sep 2022 Novi Sad, Serbia

Front-End Engineer, IT Engine

- Executed a successful migration from a multi-page user experience to a single-page app using React, leading to an impressive 8% enhancement in customer engagement.
- Rebuilt 4-year old SaaS application in React and Redux with full user experience redesign to release a beat MVP in 8 months

Feb 2017 - Nov 2019 Novi Sad, Serbia

Software Engineer, Vega IT

- Ensured the technical feasibility of 150+ UI/UX designs.
- Utilized HTML, CSS/SASS, and JavaScript to create 100+ responsive landing pages for both company and client.

Apr 2016 - May 2016 Subotica, Serbia

Software Developer Internship, HTEC Group

- · Joined an initial wave of seven developers learning and implementing the React.is library.
- Integrated Redux for state management, optimizing application performance and reducing load time by 42%.

SKILLS

Languages: (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, PHP, Python, Dart)

Technologies: (React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, React Query, Redux, React Native, Flutter, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Git, Yarn, Jest)

EDUCATION

Oct 2013 - Jun 2016 Novi Sad, Serbia

Bachelor's Applied in Information Technologies and Systems, **Information Technology,** Tech College of Applied Sciences Novi Sad